Preliminary Guide to the Neal E. Miller Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Inventory
  - President's Science Advisory Committee [PSAC]
    - Life Sciences Panel - correspondence w. James Hartgering, Office of the Special Asst. For Science and Technology, the White House, 1961-1964 (Box 8)
    - Behavioral Sciences Report - Correspondence after Publication, 1962 (Box 8)
    - Minutes of Meetings - Behavioral Sciences Subpanel, 1961 (Box 8)
    - Behavioral Sciences Subpanel - Relevant reports from others, suggestions, etc., 1958-1961 (Box 8)
    - Life Sciences - Drug Abuse Reports 1962 (Box 8)
    - Life Sciences - Morison Subpanel on Computer Technology 1962 (Box 8)
    - Life Sciences - International Science Panel, 1962 (Box 8)
    - White House Travel [work sheets] (Box 8)
    - Life Sciences Panel - Conflict of Interest, 1963 (Box 8)
    - Life Sciences Panel 1965 [on development of scientific and technical manpower resources] (Box 8)
    - Minutes of Agriculture Subpanel, 1961 (Box 8)
    - Life Sciences Panel - 1962 [Report on "Some New Technologies and their Promise for the Life Sciences" - Published 9/12/62] (Box 8)
    - Life Sciences Panel - Materials to read (Box 8)
    - Life Sciences Panel - Minutes of meetings, April-June, 1961 (Box 8)
    - Life Sciences Panel - Reports, 1962 (Box 8)
  - World Health Organization- "Scientific Group" - Geneva, 1964 (Box 8)
  - Yale University Science Advisory Committee, 1961-1962 (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 8)
  - Misc:
    - Adams, David (Peace), 1984-1987 (Box 9)
    - Albrecht, Ivan, 1969-1972 (Box 9)
    - Atkinson, Robert, 1968 (Box 9)
    - Bailey, Clark J., 1949-1978 (Box 9)
    - Bailey, Clark J. - Letters of recommendation, 1954-1977 (Box 9)
    - Barry, Herbert III, 1966-1984 (Box 9)
    - Beach, Garnet, 1968-1971 (Box 9)
    - Berkun, Mitchell, 1953-1972 (Box 9)
    - Berntson, Gary, 1970-1975 (Box 9)
    - Blizard, David, 1971-1982 (Box 9)
    - Bogoch, Samual, 1973-1975 (Box 9)
    - Booth, David A., 1963-1982 (Box 9)
    - Campbell, Byron A, 1955-1956 (Box 9)
    - Carmona, Alfredo (Chile), 1961-1981 (Box 9)
    - Chattman, Dennis (Box 9)
    - Champion, Richard A. (Australia), 1960-1965 (Box 9)
    - Chase, Richard, 1968 (Box 9)
    - Cole, Michael, 1969 (Box 9)
    - Cook, Leonard, 1976-1983 (Box 9)
    - Coons, E.E., 1968-1978 (Box 9)
    - Crank letters, 1952-1984 (Box 9)
    - Davis, John Dwelle, 1960-1981 (Box 9)
    - Davis and Coons Replacement file, 1964-1965 (Box 9)
    - Debold, Richard C., 1966-1972 (Box 9)
    - Delacour, J. [France], 1970 (Box 9)
    - Denef, Karl, 1973 (Box 9)
    - DiCara, Leo, 1969-1979 (Box 9)
    - Dollard, John, 1969-1978 (Box 9)
    - Eisenberg, Ethel M., 1974-1976 (Box 9)
    - Estes, William, 1971 (Box 9)
    - Fonberg, Dr. Elzbieta [Poland], 1958-1982 (Box 9)
    - Fontaine, O. [Belgium], 1969-1971 (Box 9)
    - Goldberg, Richard, 1974 (Box 9)
    - Gray, Jeffrey A. [Oxford, England], 1967-1979 (Box 9)
    - Grossman, Sebastian, 1967-1980 (Box 9)
    - Gur, Ruben, 1973-1974 (Box 9)
    - Hama, Dr. Haruyo [Japan], 1973-1985 (Box 9)
    - Hirai, Prof. Hisashi [Japan], 1972-1980 (Box 9)
    - Jiminez, Prof. Carmina [Puerto Rico], 1970 (Box 10)
    - John, E. Roy, 1965-1974 (Box 10)
    - Kaufman, Charles, 1968-1980 (Box 10)
    - Kasper Pandi, Dr. Phyllis [Canada], 1968-1969 (Box 10)
    - Kendler, Howard, 1952-1957 (Box 10)
    - Khilchevskaja, Rada [USSR], 1971-1973 (Box 10)
    - de Kloet, Ronald, 1973-1975 (Box 10)
    - Kohn, Sorel [Venezuela], 1972-1974 (Box 10)
    - Konorski, Jerzi [Poland], 1957-1973 (Box 10)
    - Kone, Eugene [Book on relationship of applied to basic research], 1971-1973 (Box 10)
    - Kozlovskaya, Inessa [USSR], 1966-1984 (Box 10)
    - Kriekhaus, Edward.E., 1962-1969 (Box 10)
    - Kriegstein, Arnold, 1966-1968 (Box 10)
    - Kveim, Olav [Norway], 1963-1965 (Box 10)
    - Lagerspetz, Kirsti [Finland], 1976-1981 (Box 10)
    - Levak, Milena [Brazil], 1965-1966 (Box 10)
    - Lieblich, Israel [Hebrew University of Jerusalem], 1973 (Box 10)
    - Lynch, Wesley, 1970-1979 (Box 10)
    - McPhail, Euan [England], 1965-1968 (Box 10)
    - Matsuyama, Yoshinori [Japan] (Box 10)
    - Morrell, Frank, 1969 (Box 10)
    - Meehl, Paul E., 1948-1952 (Box 10)
    - Motoyoshi, Ryoji [Japan], 1957-1958 (Box 10)
    - Mowrer, O. Hobart, 1955-1969 (Box 10)
    - Murray, Edward J., 1959-1982 (Box 10)
    - Nemko, Martin, 1970-1972 (Box 10)
    - Olpe, Dr. Hans-Rudolf [Switzerland], 1974 (Box 10)
    - Paolino, Ronald, 1962-1975 (Box 10)
    - Pappas, Bruce, 1968-1975 (Box 10)
    - Perera, Thomas B., 1972-1973 (Box 10)
    - Pfaff, Donald W., 1966 (Box 10)
    - Pines, Maya, 1970 (Box 10)
    - Plapinger, Dr. Linda, 1973-1977 (Box 10)
    - Ploog, Dr. Detlev [Germany], 1971 (Box 10)
    - Pohorecky, Dr. Larissa [Ukraine], 1970-1981 (Box 10)
    - Potolicchio, Samuel, 1972-1980 (Box 10)
    - Prescott, Dr. Robert G.S. [Cambridge, England], 1964-1965 (Box 10)
    - Quartermain, David [New Zealand], 1966-1977 (Box 10)
    - Richter, Melissa, 1955-1959 (Box 10)
    - Roberts, Alan H., 1973-1981 (Box 10)
    - Ross, Sherman, 1960-1969 (Box 10)
    - Schupf Smith, Nicole, 1967-1969 (Box 10)
    - Schuri, Uwe [West Germany], 1975-1976 (Box 10)
    - Siegel, Jerome, 1977 (Box 10)
    - Silva, Maria [Brazil], 1967-1972 (Box 10)
    - Slangen, Joseph L. [Netherlands], 1965-1973 (Box 10)
    - Solomon, Richard L., 1968 (Box 10)
    - Spence, Kenneth W., 1954-1957 (Box 10)
    - Stone, Eric A., 1967-1979 (Box 10)
    - Stricker, Edward M. [Canada], 1967-1983 (Box 10)
    - Taub, Edward, 1984 (Box 10)
    - Trotter, Dr. John - Faculty Psychology [Australia], 1959-1968 (Box 10)
    - Trowill, Dr. Jay, 1964-1979 (Box 10)
    - Vandercar, David H., 1969-1982 (Box 11)
    - Vertes, Robert, 1968-1984 (Box 11)
    - Waldbillig, Robert, 1973-1983 (Box 11)
    - Wolf, George, 1967-1984 (Box 11)
    - Wyner, Steven, 1968 (Box 11)
    - Wyrwicka, Dr. Wanda [Poland], 1975 (Box 11)
    - Yen, Miss Jen-Shew [R. of China], 1968-1979 (Box 11)
    - Zubn, Dr. Joseph, 1966 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous: A-Z, 1984-1985 (Box 11)
  - Departmental administration -- letters of recommendation, appointments, applicants
    These records are closed until processed.
    - Letters of Recommendation, A-Z, 1970-1980 (Box 45)
    - Letters of Recommendation, A-Z, 1965-1969 (Box 45)
    - Letters of Recommendation, Miscellaneous [Multiple in same letter], 1958-1967 (Box 46)
    - Letters of Recommendation, 1958-1960 (Box 46)
    - Postdoctoral Fellowships 1965, 1964-1965 (Box 46)
    - Bursary Aides, Current, 1965 (Box 46)
    - Research Fellowships, Predoctoral, 1957-1965 (Box 46)
    - Research Assistants, Current, 1963-1964 (Box 46)
    - Personnel, [Grants] MY 647 and MY 2949, 1955-1966 (Box 46)
    - Research Assistants (Applicants) - Rating charts from 1949 (Box 46)
    - Physiological Psychology - Young Candidates, 1959-1961 (Box 46)
    - Committee on Permanent Appointments: Science Appointments, 1961 (Box 46)
    - Joint Board of Permanent Officers, 1961 (Box 46)
    - Psychology Department - Students being reviewed for Admission, 1965 (Box 46)
    - Psychology Department - Certification of Students in Learning [Ph.D. program], 1959-1961 (Box 46)
  - Research Grants, General, 1952 (Box 11)
  - Miller, Neal E.- Security Questions [Sec'y of Defense Office], 1950 (Box 11)
  - [Clark] Hull's Students [Curriculum Vitaes] (Box 11)
  - Yale University: Committee on Biological Sciences, [Ph.D degree program], 1959-1963 (Box 11)
  - Dollard, John - Abnormal Psychology, Syllabi and Quizzes, 1945-1947 (Box 11)
  - Psychology Department, Annual Reports and Progress Reports, 1962-1965 (Box 11)
  - Psychology Department - Department Meetings, 1951-1964 (Box 11)
  - Animal Quarters - SHM, 1962-1966 (Box 11)
  - Foreign National Acceptance - Bureau of Foreign Nationals, 1963-1965 (Box 11)
  - Psychology Department Appointments (Budget), 1963 (Box 11)
  - Experimental Area Committee, 1963-1965 (Box 11)
  - Graduate School - Faculty meetings, etc., 1951-1965 (Box 11)
  - Psychology Department - Child Development Committee, 1953-1960 (Box 11)
  - Psychology Department - Curriculum Committee, 1949-1956 (Box 11)
  - Report of Subcommittee on Learning and Behavior (Box 11)
  - Psychology Department - MAT Program, 1954 (Box 11)
  - Psychology Department - Ph.D. Program, 1965-1966 (Box 11)
  - Psychology Department - Positions, 1961 (Box 11)
  - Psychology Department - Professors' Meetings, 1965 (Box 11)
  - Psychology Department - Replacement File (Vitae), 1964 (Box 11)
  - Psychology Department - Procedures, 1948-1965 (Box 11)
  - Psychology Department - Psychotherapy Committee, 1956 (Box 11)
  - Miller - Some Motivational Effects of Brain Stimulation and Drugs [paper and talk in Chicago], 1960 (Box 11)
  - Saccharine Manuscript 1958 ["Effects of Saccharine on 'Hunger'"], 1958-1964 (Box 11)
  - Jacobs, Martin - Experiment [Start of Old Experiments], 1956 (?) (Box 11)
  - Jensen, D.D. - Wave Form Study Data on Paper: An Experimental Design Comparing Threshold Changes Following Stimulation by Lilly's Waveform and by 60-Cycle, 1956 (Box 11)
  - Jensen, D. - Injection as Cue and Reward, Experimental Procedure, 1956 (Box 11)
  - Jensen, D. - Cats - Injections as Drive (Instrumental Response Measure), Cue and Reward, 1956 (Box 11)
  - Jensen, D.D.; Lacy; Miller, N. E.; and Richter (1956). Summer work of 1955, Ventricular Injections of Saline and Water, Effect on Thirst, 1955-1956 (Box 11)
  - Karsh /Kagan, E. Starvation, Measure of Stress (Box 12)
  - Kesson, M.
    - Exploratory Learning, 1951-1953 (Box 12)
    - Exploratory Balloon Project (Box 12)
    - Exploratory Consummatory Exps., using Dextrose, saline, salt-free diet, and Mazola oil (Box 12)
    - Bar-pressing Exp. With Mazola oil (Box 12)
    - Exploratory Milk-drinking Experiment (Box 12)
    - Withdrawal Experiment (Box 12)
    - Saccharine Experiment and Straight Line Drinking Data (Box 12)
    - Stomach Distension Experiment, 1952 (Box 12)
    - Stomach Distension in the Rat - Balloon Exp. II (Box 12)
  - Kohn, M. Pedal Pushing (Box 12)
  - Kohn and Krehl, Esophageal Maze Experiment, 1950 (Box 12)
  - Godbeer, Elizabeth, and Miller, Conflict in Life [for Conflict Monograph], 1939 (Box 12)
  - Miller, Conflict Studies - Experiments involving conflict apparatus, 1939 (Box 12)
  - Hypothalamic lesion: Decrease in behavioral measures of hunger - Miller, N.E., and Stevenson, J.A.F., 1950 (Box 12)
  - Miller, N.E. - Brain Stimulation, Oct. 1956 - Observations on the "Motor Cortex" of rats (Box 12)
  - Levin, Jane and Trapold, Milton - Secondary Reinforcement, 1958 (Box 12)
  - Miller, N.E. - Acquired Drive: Fear, Flickering Lights Experiment, 1938-1939 (Box 12)
  - Miller, N.E. - Acquired Drive: Wheel turning and bar pressing, 1941 (Box 12)
  - Miller, N.E. - Reaction Formation, 1930's (Box 12)
  - Miller, N.E. and Kessen, W. - Is Distension of Stomach by Balloon Rewarding or Punishing?, 1951 (Box 12)
  - Miller, N.E., et al. Stomach Contractions; Balloon Experiment, 1954 (Box 12)
  - Richter, Melissa - Experimental Data, 1954 (Box 12)
  - Macmillan, Trapold - Thirst Experiments - Stomach Distension, etc. (Box 13)
  - Tolbert - Acquired Drive: Black-Red Compartments, 1946? (Box 13)
  - Tolbert - Acquired Drive: Delay and Distance on, 1946? (Box 13)
  - Tolbert, Jean and Lawrence - Acquired Drive: Effect of Massed and Spaced Trials on Red-Black, 1946 (Box 13)
  - Tolbert, Jean - Acquired Drive: White-Black Compartments, 1946 (Box 13)
  - Tousley - Stress: Learning to Resist Pain and Fear - 2nd Exp., 1959 (Box 13)
  - Trapold, Miller, and Coons - Conflict 100 ft. Alley, Semi-Condensed Data, 1959-1960 (Box 13)
  - Trapold, Miller, and Coons - Approach-Avoidance Conflict in a 100 ft. Runway, Paper, 1959-1960 (Box 13)
  - Trapold - Summer Data 1959 (Box 13)
  - Trapold - Conflict Titration Study, 1959 (Box 13)
  - Trapold - Central Elicited Ejaculation (Box 13)
  - Trapold, Milton - Pavlov (Box 13)
  - Trapold, M. and Levin, Jane - Conditioned Suppression of Thirst (Box 13)
  - Trapold, M. - Conditioned Nausea: Preliminary Study, 1955 (Box 13)
  - Trapold, M. - Post-operation Fear Reduction, 1955 (Box 13)
  - Wells and Murray - Animal and Human, Saccharin Sucaryl (Box 13)
  - New York Brain Function Group, 1967-1968 (Box 13)
  - New York University Lecture Series, 1962 (Box 13)
  - SNS [Society for Neuroscience]
    - Basic Research Funds [incl. correspondence with Benno Schmidt], 1977-1981 (Box 13)
    - Affiliate Membership, 1972-1981 (Box 13)
    - Budget Committee, 1972 (Box 13)
    - Bylaws, 1974 (Box 13)
    - Committee on Communication, 1971-1973 (Box 13)
    - Committee on Education, 1972 (Box 13)
    - Minutes of Council Meetings, 1972 (Box 13)
    - Council Meetings, 1972-1976 (Box 13)
    - Fund Raising, 1972-1979 (Box 13)
    - General, 1971-1985 (Box 13)
    - Grant Foundation, 1972-1976 (Box 13)
    - Grass Foundation [for traveling lectureship], 1972-1973 (Box 13)
    - Guidelines, 1982 (Box 13)
    - Local Chapters, 1971-1977 (Box 13)
    - Committee on Journal Sponsorship, 1973-1974 (Box 13)
    - Membership Forms, 1972-1975 (Box 13)
    - Newsletter, 1971-1972 (Box 13)
    - Officers, 1972-1974 (Box 13)
    - Congress Seminar [workshop for congressional staff people], 1976-1978 (Box 13)
    - Ms. on "The Scientist's Responsibility for Public Information", 1978-1979 (Box 13)
    - Seminar for Science Writers, May 3-6, 1976 (Box 13)
    - Science Writers Handbook (Box 13)
    - Public Info, Press Seminar, 1974-1975 (Box 13)
    - Mailings, 1976 (Box 13)
    - Committee on Public Information - 1978 Program Info (Box 13)
    - Committee on Public Information - 1977-1978 (Box 14)
    - Committee on Public Information - 1976-1977 (Box 14)
    - Committee on Public Information - 1976 (Box 14)
    - Committee on Public Information - 1975 (Box 14)
    - Committee on Public Information - 1972-1974 (Box 14)
    - Sloan Foundation, 1972-1973 (Box 14)
    - Committee on Social Responsibility, 1972 (Box 14)
    - Meetings 1971 [incl. first annual meeting] (Box 14)
    - Symposia Publication, 1975 (Box 14)
  - NAS [National Academy of Sciences]
    - Proceedings, 1985 (Box 14)
    - Baker Award, 1982 (Box 14)
    - Nominating Committee, 1969-1970 (Box 14)
    - 1981 (Box 14)
    - 1970, 1970-1980 (Box 14)
    - General Folder 1965, 1965-1969 (Box 14)
    - General Folder 1964 (Box 14)
    - Education in Science and Math, 1982 (Box 14)
    - Section of Psychology 1965, 1964-1985 (Box 14)
    - Committee on Human Rights, 1977 (Box 14)
  - IOM [Institute of Medicine, part of NAS]
    - Annual Meeting, 1984 (Box 14)
    - Board on Mental Health and Behavioral Medicine, 1981-1983 (Box 14)
    - DHEW Health Research Planning, 1980 (Box 14)
    - Research on Mental Illness and Addiction [final report], 1984 (Box 14)
    - Committee to study "Health and Behavior: A Research Agenda", 1979-1981 (Box 14)
    - Members, 1984 (Box 14)
  - Artwork related to experiments with students - Miller - Diagram of apparatus (Box 14)
  - X-rays of rat, 1968 (?) (Box 14)
  - Psychotherapy Book - Drawings and Figures (Box 14)
  - Comments on Theoretical Models Illustrated by the Development of a Theory of Conflict Behavior [includes photos of diagrams] (Box 14)
  - Wolf, G. And Quartermain, D. [includes photos of diagrams], 1965 (Box 14)
  - Electrodes in Brain of Rat - Technique Photo of drawing by E.E. Coons, Fall 2956 (for Houston M.S.), 1956 (Box 14)
  - Diagrams - Animal Studies rel. to APA Symposium 1955 - Psychoanalysis (Box 14)
  - Diagrams for Berkun, Kessen, and Miller manuscript (Box 14)
  - Diagrams for Miller, Bailey, Stevenson - Decreased Hunger but Increased Food Intake (Box 14)
  - Photos and Diagrams: NY Academy Of Sciences - Effects of Drugs on Motivation: Value of Using a Variety of Measures, 1956 (Box 14)
  - Diagrams for Jensen, Lacy, Miller, and Richter- The Effect of Ventricular Injections on Thirst (Spoon Pull) - for EPA, 1956 (Box 14)
  - Miller, N.E., and Potter - Failure to Find an Asymptote in 375 Trials [photo negatives] - for EPA, 1956 (Box 14)
  - Miller, N.E.; Choy, M.; and Berman, J. - [Figures for] Drugs and Motivation: Benzedrine - Effects of Drugs on Motivation: Value of V.M., 1956 (Box 14)
  - Miller, N.E., and Kessen, W. - "Effects of Drugs on Motivation" - NY Academy of Sciences, 1956 - Figs. 1 and 2 (Box 14)
  - Photographs: Electrical Stimulation of Cat Brain - Roberta, 1955 (Box 15)
  - Figs. For Houston Symposium, 1956 - Experimental Design Comparing Lilly's Wavefore and 60-cycle Sine Wave A.C. [Miller et al.] (Box 15)
  - Reward Effects of Food Via Stomach Compared - Miller, N.E., and Kesson, M., Figs. in JCPP 1952 (Box 15)
  - Stomach Fistula: Division 3 Talk, 1953 - Diagrams and Photos (Box 15)
  - Displacement - Theory and Experiments relating Psychology - Original Drawings (Box 15)
  - Berkun, M. Thesis: Factors in the Recovery from Approach-Avoidance Conflict [negatives], 1956 (Box 15)
  - Murray, E.J. and Berkun, M. - APA Symposium - Displacement as Function of Conflict [negatives], 1955 (Box 15)
  - Photographs: Stomach Fistula Technique - Rats, 1955 (Box 15)
  - Nagaty, Mohamed - Figure [neg.] in Psychology Review II, 1951 (Box 15)
  - Photos for Hilgard, Introduction to Psychology [Harcourt and Brace], showing implanting electrodes in rat brain, 1967 (Box 15)
  - Miller - Theory and Experiment relating Psychoanalytic Displacement to S-R Generalization [photos, negs., diagrams] (Box 15)
  - Miller - Studies of fear as an acquirable drive: I. Fear as motivation and fear-reduction as reinforcement in the learning of new responses (Box 15)
  - Displacement Studies - Photographs, negs., and originals (Box 15)
  - Diagram of Kaufman's Apparatus (Box 15)
  - Kaufman and Miller - Effect of Number of Reinforced Trials on Approach - JCPP 1948 [diagrams] (Box 15)
  - Displacement articles: Miller and Murray, Murray and Miller, Miller and Kraeling [figures and diagrams] (Box 15)
  - Miller and Myers - Failure to Find Learned Drive Based on Hunger: Evidence for Learning Motivated by Exploration [diagrams] (Box 15)
  - Thirst Reducing Effects of Water by Stomach Fistula vs. Water by Mouth Measured by Both - Miller, N.E., Sampliner, R.I., and Woodrow, P. [photos], 1955 (Box 15)
  - Extinction of Preservative Wheel Turning [figs.] (Box 15)
  - Anxiety and Learning (Fisher Design) - Instructions and Exploratory Data (Box 15)
  - Miller, N.E. - Fear as a Learned Drive, Resistance to Extinction [diagrams] (Box 15)
  - Miller, N.E. - Conflict Monograph - Chapter 1 [first draft of ms.] (Box 15)
  - Drinking Experiment I [data] (Box 15)
  - Drinking Experiment II [data] (Box 15)
  - Drive During Training and Testing on Learned Reward in Acquired Drive Apparatus - Data from Summer Ex. (Box 15)
  - Raw Data (Box 15)
  - Conflict Studies and other early ones (Photographs, negs., originals (Box 15)
  - Pickering - Negatives for Goldwater project (Box 15)
  - American Orthopsychiatric Association 1961 - Graphs used for slides for talk (Box 15)
  - APA 1960 - Conflict Behavior and Drugs - negatives and photos (Box 15)
  - Barry, Herbert - Drug Study 1963 [diagrams] (Box 15)
  - Carmona [diagrams] (Box 15)
  - Central Stimulation and other New Approaches to Motivation and Reward - American Psychology article - Miller, 1957 [photos and negs.] (Box 15)
  - Chili 1963 [diagrams used in talks] (Box 15)
  - APA 1960 - Studies of Conflict Behavior and Drugs [original graphs] (Box 15)
  - Coons and Miller - ECS Photos (Box 15)
  - DeBold and Miller, Stricker and Miller [original graphs], 1965 (Box 15)
  - DeGroot Atlas [of Rat Brain] - Ozalid Masters - Hypothalamus (Box 15)
  - Displacement - Theory and Experiment relating Psychology - prints and negatives (Box 15)
  - Dose Response Studies - original graphs - norepinephrine and carbachol studies (Box 15)
  - Dose Response Study 1963 (Box 15)
  - Kirschner, Robert - Drug studies and electrical stimulation [graphs, photos, originals], 1957 (Box 15)
  - Grossman, S. - Photos [not used] (Box 15)
  - Mexico City, 1961 - original diagram (Box 15)
  - Moscow Talk - duplicate photos (Box 15)
  - Graphs from which slides were made for talk on the Experimental Analysis of Motivation - Sea Island, Georgia - ADMA (Box 15)
  - Photographs, slides, data, experiments on Motivation, etc. (Box 15)
  - Novin - Photographs - JCPP article 1961 (Box 15)
  - International Symposium, Milan '57 on Psychotropic Drugs - [graphs], 1957 (Box 15)
  - Telescope Alley Experiments - original graphs (Box 15)
  - Texas Talk, 1961 - original diagram (Box 15)
  - U. of Pennsylvania talk - negatives, photographs (Box 15)
  - Science article 1957 - original figures (Box 15)
  - Science 1965 - graphs (Box 15)
  - Science 1965 - champcal coding (Box 15)
  - Steinbaum and Miller 1964 - [original graphs] (Box 15)
  - Wolf - Lesions [original graphs] (Box 15)
  - Chien and Miller [original graphs] - EPA, 1965 (Box 15)
  - Graphs for Sigma Xi, 1968 (Box 15)
  - Miller and Senf 1964 (Box 15)
  - Myers, A.K. 1956 (Box 15)
  - Photographs of NEM, Miscellaneous (Box 16)
  - Photographs of NEM, other Psychologists of IHR, Yale (Box 16)
  - Photographs - P.R. [Public Relations] (Box 16)
  - Photos taken by Eric Holmes [in Rockefeller lab] (Box 16)
  - NRP [Neurosciences Research Program] Photographs, 1967-1968 (Box 16)
  - [Photo of Presidents of Society for Neuroscience at 25th Anniversary Meeting (Box 16)
  - Bruce McEwen - Photos of Corticosterone in Hippocampus (Box 16)
  - J. Weiss's Stomach Lesions in Rats - Photos and slides [Neesima Lectures] (Box 16)
  - Summer Help 1973-1974 and other Volunteers [back to correspondence], 1973-1984 (Box 16)
  - Summer Neighborhood Program, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Applications: Summer Help, 1969 (Box 16)
  - Inventory List, 1975 (Box 16)
  - Career Summaries 1964 -- [Vitae or recommendations for Barry, Coons, DeBold, Ellison, Gallistel, Goldberg, Healey, Kriekhaus, Leaton, Osman, Siegel, Steiner, Stricker, Thomas, Trowill, and Wolf] (Box 16)
  - Adjunct Physicians, 1976-1979 (Box 16)
  - Bailey, William H. [Adjunct Faculty], 1974-1983 (Box 16)
  - Ball, Gordon [Adjunct Faculty], 1965-1982 (Box 16)
  - Brines, Michael L.[Ph.D. program, Adjunct Faculty], 1975-1983 (Box 16)
  - Brucker, Bernard, 1976-1985 (Box 16)
  - Buccigrossi, Michael, 1983 (Box 16)
  - Charry, Jonathan, 1977 [Adjunct Faculty], 1977-1984 (Box 16)
  - Colgan, Michael [Adjunct Faculty], 1980-1986 (Box 16)
  - Davis, Adam, 1983 (Box 16)
  - Dworkin, Barry, 1978-1985 (Box 16)
  - Filewich, Robert A, 1975-1980 (Box 16)
  - Glazer, Howard, 1972-1982 (Box 16)
  - Halperin, Ronnie, 1978-1983 (Box 16)
  - Harshfield, Gregory, 1978-1979 (Box 16)
  - Jonas, Gerald, 1975-1976 (Box 16)
  - Leibowitz, Sarah, 1969-1985 (Box 16)
  - Luine, Victoria, 1971-1978 (Box 16)
  - Maclusky, Neil, 1974-1977 (Box 16)
  - Maunz, Roger, 1977-1978 (Box 16)
  - McEwen, Bruce, 1966-1980 (Box 16)
  - Meyer, Jerrold, 1975-1977 (Box 16)
  - Micco, David, 1972-1984 (Box 16)
  - Pickering, Thomas G., 1972-1978 (Box 16)
  - Rosenthal, Ronald, 1979-1986 (Box 16)
  - Singh, Ratan, 1983-1984 (Box 16)
  - Weiss, Jay, 1966-1986 (Box 16)
  - Winson, Jonathan, 1967-1984 (Box 16)
  - National Science Medal [NEM the first psychologist to receive it], 1964-1965 (Box 17)
  - Kenneth Craik Award and lecture at Cambridge, England - "Chemical Coding of Behavior in the Brain", 1966-1967 (Box 17)
  - Craik Award - Subsidiary Arrangements, 1966-1967 (Box 17)
  - McAlpin Medal [Mental Health Association Research Achievement Award], 1978-1979 (Box 17)
  - Miller, N.E. - Personal Correspondence [Maine, letters to public officials, letters re salary at Yale], 1959-1983 (Box 17)
  - Washington, U. Of - Alumnus summa laude dignitatus - June 1966 (Box 17)
  - NEM - Political letters, 1872 (Box 17)